Ford TV the world is
thinking the other part of it is where I
have to blame my my colleagues in the
economics profession uh not all
economists got it wrong um but uh a lot
of them did and they provided
arguments uh that politicians used and
people in the industry used for
stripping it away the basic argument was
a very simple one it's a variant of of
Adam Smith that uh markets unfettered
markets always lead to efficient
outcomes uh and that's why you could
have people like Alan Greenbank saying
uh there's no such thing as a bubble a
little froth in the economy uh and uh uh
the result uh of uh that gave you might
say uh sucker to the to to th those who
didn't want to engage in regulation so
you both Stripped Away regulation and
you appointed people who didn't believe
in in regulation and they could feel
good because they were just doing what
they said economic theory said you ought
to be doing but this goes back to what
you were saying uh the theories that
said that markets work perfectly were
all based on very simplistic models of
perfect
competition uh perfect markets and
information uh you know my own work uh
like I did with my colleague at Bruce
Greenwall at Columbia is that we argued
we showed that the reason that uh when
there's imperfect information asymmetric
information and these other problems the
reason that the Invisible Hand the idea
that Mark that the pursuit of
self-interest would lead as if by an
invisible hand to the well-being of
everybody in society the reason the
Invisible Hand often seemed invisible
was that it wasn't there and uh I don't
think today anybody would claim that the
pursuit of self-interest by the bankers
which is sometimes called greed has led
to the well-being of all
Society uh and yet this was the central
notion taught in almost every graduate
school in the
country